feedthepig.org 2012-11-26

# AICPA and CPA2Biz Joint Privacy Policy

**Overview**  
The Joint Privacy Policy of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants (AICPA) and CPA2Biz describes how these organizations and their affiliates (we) collect, use and share personally identifiable information that you provide via the use of our websites (the “Sites”) through membership, volunteerism, conference/webinar attendance, purchases and other interactions in which information is collected. The term “you” indicates website visitors, AICPA members, customers, candidates, affiliates, associates, volunteers, authors and any user of the Sites or anyone doing business with the organizations.  “You” does not include the organizations’ employees, vendors, contractors or persons in similar business relationships where personally identifiable information may be provided and used.  The AICPA and CPA2Biz are based in the United States and as such this policy was developed under the laws of the United States.  The Joint Privacy Policy is subject to change periodically. The Joint Privacy Policy is posted on the Sites and is effective at the time denoted by its date. It is recommended that you regularly check the Sites for updates. 

**Notice**  
The use of the Sites and services offered by the organizations constitutes your acceptance of the Joint Privacy Policy. If you use the Sites, register, login, post comments, participate in forums, wikis or blogs, register for courses, exams or other events, purchase products, apply for membership, become a member, or otherwise submit personally identifiable information in any manner, you are consenting to the use of such data in accordance with this Joint Privacy Policy.  If you are an international user, the use of any website covered by this Joint Privacy Policy constitutes consent to this Joint Privacy Policy and an acknowledgement that use of any website covered by the Joint Privacy Policy is solely subject to the laws governing the use of data in the United States and as indicated by this policy. 

Additionally, the Sites contain links to other websites managed by third parties (some of which use of cookies).  As a user of links, it is your responsibility to understand the privacy policies of the websites you visit.  Once you leave our website using links, we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by any third parties and we are not responsible for activities or practices of those other websites. 

The scope of this Joint Privacy Policy does not include websites that are owned, and/or managed by related entities or third parties unless such entities or third party links to this policy.  Also, it does not include AICPA program or marketing related websites for the development of interest in the CPA profession and careers (such as, but not limited to, [www.startheregoplaces.com](http://www.startheregoplaces.com/) which are governed by their own privacy policies). 

**Collection of Personally Identifiable Information**   
We collect and maintain demographic information and personally identifiable information such as, but not limited to, your name, date of birth, email address, home and business address (including country), and telephone, cell and fax numbers.  Additionally, we collect credit card, bank account and other payment information and other business information that you provide for transactional purposes such as, but not limited to, purchases, conferences, applications, examinations and membership.  We also collect personally identifiable information from authors, vendors, contractors and from vendors via purchased or rented lists.

The minimum information you need to provide to complete any specific transaction or access any particular area of the Sites is detailed on the Sites’ pages or forms. You will be unable to place an order or complete a registration without providing minimal information required for the transaction. In some cases, other optional information is also requested, which you may elect to provide.  This optional information allows us to provide a more personalized experience for the website user.

Your preferences are collected through information you provide via your membership and “My Account” submissions, website registration, purchases, conference/webinar registration/attendance, tradeshows, examinations, credential registration, participation in committees/special interest groups and task forces, subscriptions, scholarship and fellowship applications, online surveys, as well as other information you provide.  Some of these functions, forms or activities provide for opt-outs as to providing information.  If opt-outs are utilized, certain websites, benefits and/or website functionality may not be available.  We also collect and use personally identifiable information as part of various programs such as, but not limited to, contests, peer review, ethics inquiries and investigations, award nominations, volunteer and committee activities and benevolent fund and foundation applications and donations. 

**Online Networking Features  
**By participation in networking functions such as, but not limited to, initiating your public profile, posting your resume, posting a comment or review, participating in a community activities, discussion forums, blogs, wikis or similar activity, be advised that information you provided may be publicly viewable when using these functionalities.  This includes information such as, but not limited to, username or other information you have used as your username (e.g., email address or your name).  This may result in unsolicited messages or communication beyond our control. 

**Collection of Passive Information  
**Upon any use of the Sites, providing email address, enrolling in programs, or completing various forms, we collect non-identifying information through the use of cookies technology and/or Internet Protocol (IP) address tracking/URL tracking.  This technology collects non-personal information such as, but not limited to, new or returning user, browser information, computer type, operating system, internet service providers, website usage, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, number of clicks, advertisement viewing, and performance to personalize the content to better serve you and all website users.  We collect this information to perform effective capacity planning, administer the Sites, troubleshoot website performance, track aggregate users' movements, gather aggregate demographics and accurately document transactional information for business partners. 

**The Use of Cookies for Advertising**  
Our Sites may contain advertisements, whose related cookies may collect data, but also track your movement and behavior on other sites. These types of cookies, from third-party advertisers or from links accessed via our Sites, are not controlled by us. 

We utilize our own cookies to track visitor behavior on aicpa.org to optimize your experience on our site and provide promotional advertising on other sites for AICPA and CPA2Biz products or services. To accomplish this, we partner with various third party vendors, including Google and DoubleClick, who use these cookies to display relevant ads based on your browsing sessions on aicpa.org.

If you do not want to save site-related cookies on your hard drive, you can adjust your browser settings to delete and/or not accept cookies.  However, if you adjust your browser in this manner, we cannot guarantee that all applications on the Sites will function properly for you and your experience may not be optimized. Additionally, the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) provides an “Opt-out Tool” that was developed to allow consumers to "opt out" of the behavioral advertising delivered by the NAI member companies such as Google and DoubleClick ([http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/)).

**Use of Information and Sharing and Disclosure to Third Parties  
**We use personally identifiable information collected for membership, non-member/customer activity, and account maintenance.  We may communicate with you regarding membership benefits, any program enrollment or special interest group, or account billing and maintenance and potential membership.  We also communicate with members regarding peer review or ethics inquiries, violations and/or sanctions.  We use and maintain various records regarding interactions such as, but not limited to, continuing professional education.  In addition, we use and maintain your information as determined by the organizations’ business needs, or as required or permitted by law.  Some member information or customer transaction email or communications are not available for opt out (see Choice and Opt Out, below). 

Information is used to process transactions/orders, send conference/webinar information, subscriptions, periodicals and other information, noting that credit card/banking/payment information is restricted for the purchase/uses identified.  We often facilitate billing and payment of transactions through the use of third parties responsible for processing credit card, banking and payment information and invoicing transactions. 

We use collected information to build quality and useful services and user interactions by analyzing user trends and by measuring demographics and interests.  We analyze demographics, user trends, and member and non-member purchases to develop interest areas for referral listings and to offer suggestions on specialty membership or product areas. We may use information you provide or passive information collected to improve and offer additional services to you and may contact you directly. We often share member information with state CPA societies so that they may also contact you regarding offerings or membership in your state. Individual state CPA societies are separate and distinct entities and are not included in the Joint Privacy Policy.  Users should read and review each state society’s privacy policy and practices and may need to opt-out under such policies and practices separately.

We personalize various aspects of the Sites by pre-populating online forms for your convenience and for member validation.  We use information to provide you with prompt and effective services. We may use non-identifying profile information in the aggregate (such as interest area information) and disclose such aggregated information to third parties to assist in developing new features and content, as well as information on trends and usage patterns.

Collected information is used to send newsletters, promotional messages, product announcements, request for contributions or other communications that may be of interest to you.  We also use information collected to refer you to our specialty membership areas.  We request participation in online surveys and communicate as defined by the individual survey.  You may opt out of receiving some of these communications (see Choice and Opt Out below).

We share your information with third parties as permitted or required by law.  Types of disclosures, including but not limited to the following, may be made without asking for explicit consent from you:

  * As necessary pursuant to lawful requests, such as to respond to subpoenas, warrants, court  orders, or other related legal requests or proceedings and as permitted or required by law; 
  * In connection with the sale or transfer of AICPA or CPA2Biz or substantially all of their  assets; 
  * If certain other disclosures, such as, but not limited to, those connected to AICPA enforcement proceedings, are required or authorized pursuant to AICPA bylaws and resolutions of AICPA Council. As a condition of AICPA membership, you have consented to comply with the bylaws and Code of Professional Conduct, including those relevant to disciplinary actions; and 
  * If you volunteer on an AICPA committee, your name, committee, and city/state are visible to the public in the Volunteer section of aicpa.org. 

Additionally, third parties with whom we may share information include but are not limited to:

  * All AICPA and CPA2Biz affiliated organizations; 
  * Member Discount Program Partners (e.g., Affinity Partners, Shared Services, LLC); 
  * Networking communities and discussion forums vendors; 
  * Conference attendees, expert panels and fellow committee members; 
  * Mailing and fulfillment houses and third-party vendors for various communications and orders; 
  * Individuals accessing the peer review public file, firm search, and referral or resume searches; 
  * Individuals accessing the specialty member referral websites; 
  * State CPA societies and NASBA (the National Associations of State Boards of Accountancy); and 
  * XBRL International (International consortium that oversees maintenance of the technical specifications for the eXtensible Business Reporting Language (XBRL).  This also includes XBRL US which advocates the use of XBRL in the US. 

Your information may also be shared to:

  * Verify that you are a member of the AICPA and the society of the state in which you are licensed; 
  * Complete various internal and external audits; 
  * Maintain AICPA membership in the NASBA Quality Assurance service; 
  * Promote you or your firm through a specialty referral program; and 
  * Respond to technical accounting and auditing questions. 

Mailing address information may be used for direct mail list rental, which is managed by CPA2BIZ and is for one-time limited use for companies and organizations offering products, services or programs of interest to CPAs, other accountants and financial executives related to the profession’s business environment.  Third parties are bound by agreements which prohibit use of information for any purpose outside of the scope of the contracted activities. 

CPA2Biz and the AICPA share email and website usage information about visitors who have received a targeted email promotional campaign from the organizations with a third-party email service provider organization (Epsilon Interactive) for the sole purpose of targeting future email campaigns and upgrading visitor information used in reporting statistics. For this purpose, CPA2Biz and Epsilon Interactive track some of the pages you visit on our website through the use of pixel tags (also called “clear gifs”). This information is not shared with any third parties other than Epsilon Interactive.

If you are not a member of the AICPA, CPA2Biz will share with the AICPA all the information collected in connection with the sale of any product or use of website. In addition, CPA2Biz will transmit your username and payment information to the AICPA so, in the future, if you elect to become a member of the AICPA, your username on the CPA2Biz websites will be available to you for use as a username on the AICPA websites.  AICPA shares your information with CPA2Biz and other affiliates as outlined within this section. 

Your personal information may also be used or shared in other than ways that you either imply or expressly give consent to or instruct us to undertake.

**Choice and Opt-Out  
**If you have an AICPA username, you can opt out of certain  communication, including direct mail list rentals, via “My Account” on aicpa.org, by contacting the Member Service Center at 1.888.777.7077 (9 am – 6 pm EST, M-F) or by emailing [service@aicpa.org](mailto:service@aicpa.org).  If you receive a specific email regarding products, conferences or other services, you can follow the "unsubscribe" instructions at the bottom of the specific email. Opt outs for specific emails do not serve as a global opt out of communications for all products or for services communications.  To perform a global opt out, an AICPA username is required on aicpa.org, as noted above.  It will take 10 days for your email opt-out selections to take effect and longer for other communications/mailings.  Though a member may opt out of receiving communications from the AICPA, the AICPA will continue to contact the member regarding his/her account, membership, or member’s surveys for which he/she will have the opportunity to elect or decline to participate.

In addition, you can opt out of receiving future e-mailed messages or newsletters from CPA2Biz by changing your preferences in the “Preference Center,” which can be accessed from the “My Account” section of the CPA2Biz site.

**Data Accuracy  
**Individuals are responsible for providing accurate and complete personally identifiable information, and for contacting the AICPA to correct or update information as needed.  AICPA members and non-members with AICPA usernames may view and update their account information at any time by logging on to aicpa.org and clicking Update Personal Information from the My Account screen, or alternatively contact the Member Service Center at 1.888.777.7077 or [service@aicpa.org](mailto:service@aicpa.org) from (9 am – 6 pm EST, M-F) to update their accounts.

CPA2Biz registered users also can check or verify the information they have provided to CPA2Biz by signing in, then clicking on the "My Profile" page of the "My Account" tab and making any necessary edits to this information. In certain instances, if a user changes a critical piece of personal information, such as, but not limited to, name, address, and/or job function, a service representative may follow up with the user to confirm the change.

**Parents and Children  
**We strive to comply with the provisions of COPPA (the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act) and do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13.   Parents have the right to terminate the registration of a child under 13.  Please contact the Member Service Center at 1.888.777.7077 or [service@aicpa.org](mailto:service@aicpa.org) from (9 am – 6 pm EST, M-F) to instruct such termination.

**Security and Other  
**We use reasonable measures to strive to safeguard and secure the personally identifiable information we collect.  Any transmission is at your own risk.  Technology, such as, but not limited to, Secured Socket Layer (SSL), is used to enhance security and reduce risk of loss.  Our security practices, processes or technology do not guarantee absolute security of your information and you should take all normal personal precautions such as, but not limited to, not sharing passwords, closing browsers, and not using public networks (e.g., internet cafes, etc.).    
Employees of the organizations are advised to treat any personally identifiable information with care. Internally, we limit access to personally identifiable information to employees, contractors and agents who need access to the information to do their jobs or perform services on behalf of the AICPA and CPA2Biz.

Use of these Sites, with respect to privacy, is covered by binding arbitration. Users of the Sites are encouraged to report any suspected breach of privacy or site security to our Service Center Operations Team at the telephone number, e-mail address, or mailing address indicated at the bottom of this page. All reports of suspected breaches will be investigated by staff familiar with the related security operations. Any controversy or claim related to privacy that cannot be settled to your satisfaction shall be settled by arbitration in New York, New York. Such disputes will be administered by the American Arbitration Association, <http://www.adr.org/>, 335 Madison Avenue, 10th floor, New York, New York 10017-4605, (800) 778-7879, in accordance with its arbitration rules, and judgment upon the award rendered by the arbitrator(s) may be entered in any court having jurisdiction thereof.

**Consent to Transfer  
**Some of the uses and disclosures mentioned in this Joint Privacy Policy may involve the transfer of your personal information to various countries around the world that may have different levels of privacy protection than your country. By submitting your personal information through this Site or otherwise, as described above, you consent to the collection, processing, use, and transfer to the United States and other various countries of your personal information for the purposes of and in accordance with the principles stated in this Joint Privacy Policy.

**Contact Information  
**Users of these Sites are encouraged to report any improvements, suggestions, any suspected breach of privacy or website security to our Service Center Operations Team at the telephone number, email address, or mailing address indicated as follows: 

American Institute of CPAs  
220 Leigh Farm Road   
Durham, NC 27707  
P: 1.888.777.7077  
F: 1.800.362.5066  
Hours of Operation: (9 am – 6 pm, EST, M-F)  
| CPA2BIZ, Inc.  
1211 Avenue of the Americas  
New York, NY 10036  
P: 1.888.777.7077  
F: 1.800.362.5066  
Hours of Operation: (9 am – 6 pm, EST, M-F)  
---|---  
  
**Websites Covered  
**This policy covers AICPA.org, CPA2Biz.com, and all other AICPA and CPA2Biz affiliated sites that link to this policy.
